Guide to the Oakland Home Telephone Company Collection, 1893-1909
Department of Special Collections
Oakland Home Telephone Company Collection,
1893-1909
Special Collections M0175
Oakland Home Telephone Company.
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased from Alta California Bookstore, 1967.
Scope and Content
The items in this collection are dated from 1893-1909 and consist of correspondence (small amount) and business and legal documents. Under correspondence there are several letters from an injured employee, letters dealing with stockholders of Telepost, and a few letters discussing bills and agreements concerning the construction and operation of the telephone company. The business and legal documents contain various statements authorizing and acknowledging the creation of the telephone company, lists of names, minutes of different meetings, certificates of stockholders, some financial material, and other miscellaneous items.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. Jan. 17, 1899,to Mr. F.M. Gray, from M.J. Dillman. concerns introduced telephone bill which was framed by the Sunset -Pacific people
  - 2. Jan. 10, 1899,Assembly Bill, contained in letter above.
  - 3. Jan. 17, 1899,from Emma Mitchell; releases Peoples Telephone Company of payments for accident while employed by them.
  - 4. Jan. 28, 1899,from Peoples Telephone Company, (Frank M. Gray, gen.mgr.) to Mr. Theo. Halsey (manager Sunset Telephone Co.) concerns agreement
  - 5. Jan. 30, 1899,from Miss Emma Mitchell to Mr. Gray. concerns payment during her illness
  - 6. copy of 5
  - 7. Feb. 4, 1899,from Oscar C. Rodgers. copy of statement by Rodgers concerning trouble on the line of McNeil Bros.
  - 8. Feb. 4, 1899from James T. Maguire. Certification that Maguire helped string telephone wires.
  - 9. Feb. 4, 1899from G.R. Graham. assisted Maguire
  - 10. Feb. 4, 1899from Frank Thurber, Electrician, Peoples Tel. Co. concerning wire break down
  - 11. March 22, 1903from [W.E.E. Henou?] to W.A. Beasley Esq. construction of telephone system
  - 12. April 29, 1911from H. Lee Sellers to Mr. Charles C. Maynard. getting stockholders for Telepost
  - 13. May 27, 1911,from C.E. Perkins to Charles C. Maynard. concerning Maynard's shares in Telepost
  - 14. (nd)from Frank M. Gray to Thomas J. McGeoghegan concerns McGeoghegan's demand for payment of 2per cent on telephones in use
  - 15. copy of #14
  - 16. (nd)second page from unknown manager's letter concerns business and trouble with company which sold [UNK] to Peoples Telephone Co.
- BUSINESS AND LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1893-1898 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1. Thompson v. Board of Supervisors of Alameda County franchise awarded under Act of March 23, 1893
  - 2. copy of #1
  - 3. Nov. 20, 1896Articles of Incorporation of The Peoples Telephone Company
  - 4. Feb. 15, 1897,Requests of the stockholders of the Peoples Telephone Company - increasing number of Directors
  - 5. Feb. 20, 1897statement by J.R. Roberts - confirmation of existence of Peoples Telephone Co.
  - 6. Feb. 20, 1897statement J.R. Roberts acknowleding Directors of the Peoples Telephone Co.
  - 7. Feb. 20, 1897statement J.R. Roberts acknowledging subscribers[?]
  - 8. Feb. 23, 1897statement J.R. Roberts acknowledging subscribers
  - 9. Feb. 20, 1897statement J.R. Roberts acknowledging corporation
  - 10. March 1, 1897,statement by Eugene W. Levy acknowledging persons who executed annexed instrument
  - 11. March 1, 1897,Chas. W. Smyth, acknowledges Maruice V. Samuels and connection with instrument
  - 12. Aug. 22, 1898Petition for writ of mandate by the Capital Telephone and Telegraph Company
- BUSINESS AND LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1898 Aug.-1903 Mar. 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1. August, 1898,Statement of Facts discussing authorization of telephone and telegraph system in San Jose
  - 2. Dec. 22, 1898Minutes of Third Annual Meeting of the Stockholders of the Peoples Telephone Co.
  - 3. Dec. 30, 1898,Signatures of those assenting to amendment by Directors of Peoples Tel. Co.
  - 4. Jan. 4, 1899,Certificate of Decrease of Number of Directors of Peoples Telephone Co.
  - 5. copy of #4
  - 6. different copy of #4 (titled Certificate of Increase of Number of Directors of Peoples Telephone Co.) but having same wording; mistakes gone over in pencil
  - 7. Jan. 5, 1899,F.H. Benson, Notary Public in and for the County of Santa Clara, State of Calif., visited by Pres, Sec. and Directors of Peoples Tel. Co.
  - 8. copy of #7
  - 9. Dec. 22, 1898,announcement of Stockholder's meeting
  - 10. Sept. 5, 1902,Ordinance No. 1423; granting permission to Sunset Telephone and Telegraph Company to build
  - 11. Dec., 1902,Articles of Incorporation of the Oakland Home Telephone Company
  - 12. Jan. 19, 1903,Certification of receipt of Articles Incorporation of the Oakland Home Telephone Co.
  - 13. Mar. 24, 1903,Organization of Oakland Home Tel. Co.
- BUSINESS AND LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1903 Mar. 24-1909 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1. Mar.24, 1903First Stockholders' Meeting of Oakland Home Telephone Company
  - 2. Mar. 24, 1903,Director's Meeting
  - 3. April 13, 1903,Resolution for intra-state telephone, and telephone and telegraph system in city of Eureka
  - 4. (nd)Plans and Specifications for Underground Cond its, Pole and Cable Lines, Oakland Home Tel. Co.
  - 5. [?] 1903By-Laws of the Oakland Home Tel. Co.
  - 6. May 1903-May 1904Bank book for First National Bank
  - 7. 1905,Vouchers
  - 8. Feb. 19, 1909,Charles C. Maynard, Certificate of Ownership of stock (Series A. Class III)
  - 9. same as 8 (Series A. Class II)
  - 10. same as 8 (Series A. Class I)
  - 11. Feb. 23, 1909,Certificate for stock deposited under voting trust agreement of April 12, 1907 Charles Maynard
  - 12. July 21, 1909,Grover Thomas Bacon, Convertible Certificate of stock (Series A. Class III)
  - 13. same as #12 (Series A. Class II)
  - 14. same as #12 (Series A. Class I)
  - 15. July 24, 1909,Grover Thomas Bacon, same as #11
- BUSINESS AND LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1896 Dec.-1898 July 1; n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1. Dec. 1896-July 1, 1898cost [?] of phones in city
  - 2. (nd)names fo shareholders
  - 3. (nd)list of people whose telephones were removed for non-payment
  - 4. (nd)advertisement for Electric Mail
  - 5. same as #4
  - 6. same as #4
  - 7. same as #4
  - 8. (nd)An Ordinance granting to W.A. Beasly, his successors and assigns, a telephone and telegraph franchise in the City of Oakland, County of Alameda, State of California
  - 9. (nd)Contract for agreement between Kellogg Switchboard and Supply Company of Chicago and the Oakland Home Telephone Company
  - 10. (attched to #9) Specifications for a Common Battery Multiple Switchboard for the Main Exchange at Oakland, Calif.
  - 11. (nd)Signatures on petition asking City Council to grant application of the Home Telephone Co.